（レイツェル）ジンは言ってた。
私には何かが欠けてると…。
Jin told me...
that I lack something,
so he couldn't come with me.
だから　私とは
一緒に行けないって。
ジン…　もう私の事　昔みたいに
好きじゃないのかも。
Maybe he doesn't love me like he did back then.
（アナ・グラム）そんな事ないよ。→
That's not it.
ジンジンは　レイレイの事
嫌いなんかじゃない。
Jinjin doesn't hate you, Raerae.
今も　レイレイの事　だ～い好き！
アナは　そう思う。
I think... he loves you the same as before.
あなた…　何？
Who are you?
Raerae is my Catfriend
（姫川エレナ）へえ～。→
私が　サード写真集の撮影で
海外に行ってる間に→
So while I was abroad taking photos for my next album,
そんな事があったなんてねえ。
you got into all that trouble?
（キュービック・Ｇ）そうなんだよ。→
Pretty much.
こっちは　レイツェルのせいで
毎日　大変なんだから。
Every day is a challenge for us thanks to Raetsel.
（エレナ）
なら　一つ　質問があるんだけど。
（井藤ノノハ）ん？
I've got just one question then.
Can you explain that?
あれ　一体どういう事？
はい　あ～ん。
Say "ah"!
あっ　レイレイ　てれてる～！
（レイツェル）てれてなんかないわよ。→
Raerae, don't be so shy!
I'm not being shy.
Can you just leave me alone?
お願いだから
あっち行ってくれる？
どうなってるのよ　あの子。
私たちの敵じゃなかったわけ？
What's going on? Wasn't she the enemy?
（大門カイト）ま…　ほっとけよ。
（エレナ）はあ!?
Just leave her be.
Huh?
そう決めたんだ。
もう　あいつは関係ねえ。→
I decided that's what I'm going to do.
She can do whatever she wants.
We'll figure out the truth behind Jin without her.
俺たちだけで
ジンの真実を突き止めるんだ。
何それ！　訳分かんない。
What do you even mean?
You're not making any sense!
第一　あの子自身が
まだまだ謎だらけじゃない。→
Isn't she one of the biggest puzzles around here?
あなたたちも　気にならないわけ？
Doesn't she pique your curiosity?
それは…　そうだけど…。
Well, she does...
Talking with you guys just makes me feel dumb.
あ～　もう！　あなたたちと
話してたって　らちが明かないわ。
私が　直接　聞きに行ってくる！
I'll go ask her instead.
あ～ん。
う…。
（エレナ）ちょっと！
（アナ）お？
Excuse me.
お話があるんだけど。
May we talk?
何？　話って。
それはね…。
Talk about what?
Well, I was thinking about throwing a welcome party for you!
あなたの歓迎会を
開いてあげようと思うの。
歓迎会？
（エレナ）そう！
A welcome party?
Yup!
あなた　まだ転校してきたばかりで
右も左も分からないでしょ。
You only just transferred, and you barely know your way around the school, right?
私が　いろいろ教えてあげるわ。
だから　あなたも教えてくれる？
I'd be glad to help you out.
But in exchange, I'd like you to tell us about yourself!
あなた自身の事とか！
アナも賛成！
I agree!
（千枝乃タマキ）
私たちも賛成です。
（水谷アイリ）私たちも賛成！
So do we.
（タマキ）エレナさん！　私　感動したわ。→
Elena, I'm so touched. I didn't know you were so friendly.
あなたが　そんなに
友達思いだったなんて。
最近　レイツェルさん　元気ないから
私たち　心配してたんです。
You seemed down lately. We were really worried about you.
何か　悩みでも　あるんですか？
いえ　別に。
Is something on your mind?
Nothing in particular.
あっ！　やっぱり　あるんですね!?
I knew it!
一体　何？　何があったの？
What is it? What happened?
（アイリ）会長　そこは察して下さい。
（タマキ）えっ？
Come on, read between the lines!
（アイリ）女の子の悩みといったら
１つしかないじゃないですか。
There's only one thing that can really trouble a maiden's heart!
恋です！　恋の病です！
Love! The thing called love!
いや…　あのね…。
（タマキ）
そうだったのね　私とした事が…。
Uh, I don't think—
Ah, you're right.
How could I be so oblivious!
この一件　生徒会長として
ほうっておけません。
My pride as student council president won't allow me to ignore this case.
Let's hold this party as a symbol of our support for you!
レイツェルさんを応援するためにも
歓迎会を開催しましょう！
（アナ　アイリ）お～！
（レイツェル）ちょ…。
Let's kick up our heels today!
（アイリ）今日は　みんなで
はめを外しちゃいましょうよ。
（アナ）エレエレ　行こうよ～。
Eleele, let's go!
しょ…　しょうがないわね。
I guess I don't have a choice now, do I?
Follow my lead!
それじゃあ　みんな　まとめて
私に　ついてらっしゃい！
（アナ　タマキ　アイリ）わ～い！
フン。
（軸川ソウジ）ふぅ…。　レイツェルか…。
Raetsel might just be another of Enigma's puppets.
彼女も　エニグマの手駒の
一つなのかもしれないね。
操られてるって事？
A puppet how?
一体　何者なんだ？
エニグマって野郎は。
But who's this Enigma guy in the first place?
He's got a decent reputation as a president,
大統領としての国際的評価は
低くないね。
でも　アムギーネ共和国は
情報統制が徹底してるみたいで→
but as censorship is strong in Amgine, no one knows the truth.
その実態は　闇の中って感じだよ。
Just more puzzles, huh?
結局　こっちも謎ばっかしか。
ただ　１つだけ
確実な情報を入手したんだ。
There's just one piece of intel.
ギャモン！
Gammon! Your bounty's lower than mine now.
え？
（キュービック）僕より　賞金　下がったね。
な～に～!?
What?!
It's true!
ほんとだ。
キューちゃんが　８３万ドルで→
Cubie's now $830k while Gammon's at $640k.
ギャモン君が　６４万ドルになってる。
Why would they do that?!
何でだよ!?　俺が　キュー太郎より
下とか　ありえねえだろ！
Who'd even think Cubie's better than me?!
僕は　この前　マスターブレインに
勝ったからね。
ぐっ…。
I beat a Master Brain after all.
You haven't solved any puzzles by yourself recently.
お前　最近
１人で　パズル解いてねえもんな。
（ギャモン）て…　てめえ！　バカイト！
何だと!?　ほんとの事だろ！
Even you, Kaito?
I'm just stating a fact!
You just haven't got any enemies on your doorstep yet!
まあ　まあ…。　それは　たまたま
ギャモン君の所に　敵が来ないだけで。
ケッ！　気に入らねえ。
This makes me want to puke.
結局　やつらのお目当ては
カイトって事かよ。
All they care about is Kaito.
おい　ギャモン！
Hey, Gammon!
（ギャモン）６４万ドルは出ていくぜ。
$640k, exit stage left.
ギャモン君…。
Gammon...
（アイリ）レイツェルさ～ん！　早く　早く！
Raetsel!
Come on!
（エレナ）行きたい所があったら
言いなさいよ。
If there's anything you'd like to check out, just say so!
今日の主役は　あなたなんだから。
You're the center of attention today!
Hanging out like this is kinda like a girls' day!
でも　こうやって　みんなで
歩いてると　女子会みたいね。
アナ　男子だよ。
えっ!?
But I'm a guy...
Look at that!
（アイリ）あっ　あれ！　レイツェルさんに
似合いそうじゃないですか？
That'd look great on you, Raetsel!
Try it on, Raerae!
着てみよう。
えっ　私は…。
I just—
（アイリ）着てみましょう　レイツェルさん！
Try it on, Raetsel!
Try it on!
（レイツェル）ちょっと…。
（アナ）
わ～い！　着てみる　着てみる～！
（デモリションマン）ヒトロクマルマル。　ターゲットＤ。
その他３名の所在を確認。
1600: Target D located in the company of three others.
Capture target B!
（デモリションマン）ターゲットＢ　捕捉。
フン！
戦略　第８，３７７号を実行する
絶好の機会である。→
This is the perfect chance to execute Tactic No. 8377.
Free pool invitation ticket
すてきです
レイツェルさん。
まあまあね。
You look gorgeous, Raetsel!
Not bad.
（アイリ）わ～い！　キャハハハ！
プハー。
（エレナ）ほ～ら！
あ…。
Come on, take a dip!
あなたも　さっさと入りなさいよ。
レイレイ　とっても　プリチーなんだな。
You're really pretty, Raerae.
ねらいは何？
What do you want?
ほえ？
どうせ　何か
たくらんでるんでしょ。
I know you're scheming something.
私に近づいて　どうしたいわけ？
What do you want to achieve by getting close to me?
猫はアナの友達。
だから　レイレイもネコ友！
Cats are my friends.
So you're my catfriend too!
ふざけないで！　一体…　あっ!?
Give me a break! What doe—
（エレナ　タマキ　アイリ）あ…？
な…　何よ？
What?
レイレイ…　カイトと同じ匂いがする。
You smell the same as Kaito.
えっ？
（アナ）だから　レイレイにも→
So just like Kaito, you need some fluff-puff, love-puff too!
カイトと同じように
ふわわん　ほわわん　してほしい。
アナは　そう思うんだな。
I think... you do, at least.
てめえか？　俺を呼んだのは！
Were you the one who called me out here?
（デモリションマン）逃げずに　よく来たな。
I'm impressed you showed up.
たりめぇだ！
Of course I did!
マスターブレインも　ようやく
俺の才能に気付いたみてえだな。
The Master Brains finally took notice of my genius.
フン！
Listen now! Kind guys are the most dangerous! Watch your step!
いい？　優しい男っていうのは→
逆に　一番　地雷なんだから
気を付けなさい。
なるほど。　勉強になるわ。
I see. You're so wise.
さすが　アイドル。　経験豊富な人は
言う事が違います～。
Idols really see the world from a different angle.
ま…　まあね。
Oh, well.
まったく…。
Ah, come on.
Raetsel, it's time for us to get to the point.
さて　レイツェルさん！
あ…。
そろそろ
本題に入りたいんだけど…。
You really treasure that cat brooch, don't you?
その猫のブローチ
大事にしてるのね。
あ…　これ…。
This?
もしかして…。
Could that be...
やっぱり　そうなんですね～！
I knew it!
このブローチは　私たちの絆…。
This brooch is what binds us together.
You mustn't lose, Raetsel.
負けちゃ駄目よ　レイツェルさん。
That's right! If you love him so much, you mustn't give up!
そうですよ。
そんなに好きな人だったら→
諦めちゃ駄目です。
私　応援しますから！
うん。
I'm here to support you!
ありがとう。
Thanks...
あっ　レイレイ　笑った！
（レイツェル）えっ？
Raerae, you smiled!
Raetsel, your smile is pretty too.
レイツェルさん　笑顔も　すてきですね。
I didn't do anything special...
そんな…　別に　私は…。
心の声
（エレナ）カイト…？
Kaito?
フフフッ　全員そろったようだな。
All the pieces are on the board.
この戦闘　我が輩の勝利である。
I have won this battle.
（レイツェル）
知らないって言ってるでしょ！
I said I have no idea!
とぼけるんじゃねえ！
お前じゃなけりゃ→
Give me a break!
If it wasn't you who called us here,
俺たちを　ここに呼びつけたのは
一体　誰だっていうんだ!?
then who was it?
（一同）あっ！
罠!?
A trap?!
Target A: Daimon Kaito.
（モニター）「ターゲットＡ　大門カイト
ならびに　その他ターゲットの諸君。→
And all you other targets as well.
I am the greatest strategist of all the Master Brains, Colonel Demolitionman.
我が輩は　マスターブレイン随一の戦略家
デモリションマン大佐である」。
何ですって!?
What?!
（モニター）「この度は　我が輩の戦略に
よくぞ掛かってくれた。→
Thank you for taking the bait so easily and getting caught in my plan.
これより　諸君らの運命は
この男　ターゲットＢに託される」。
Your lives are now in the hands of Target B.
（エレナ）あっ！
ギャモン!?
Gammon!
You didn't say a word about this!
てめえ…　聞いてねえぞ！
あのビルにいるやつら全員が
人質って事かよ!?
Is everyone in that building a hostage?
That is correct.
（デモリションマン）そのとおりである。
You don't have the right to forfeit in this battle!
貴様に　この戦闘を拒否する
権利はない！→
この戦車は
パズルの開始と同時に発進。→
This tank will start moving as soon as the puzzle starts,
以後　パズルを解放するまで
止まらない。→
and won't stop until you solve it.
ターゲットＢ　もし貴様が
パズルの解放に失敗した場合は→
Unless you can solve the puzzle, it'll crash into the boiler room of the building and...
戦車が　ビルのボイラー室に突入し…。
くっ…。　てめえ！
（スピーカー・デモリションマン）「フフフフ。→
Damn you!
This is all for the sake of the great Makata Jin.
全ては　偉大なる
真方ジンのためである！→
それでは
戦闘のルールを説明しよう。→
I will now explain the rules of this battle.
このパズルは　タンクプレース。
画面内のフィールドに→
The puzzle is called Tank Place.
If you can place all the tanks on the field, then you win.
指定された戦車を
全て配置すれば　完成だ。→
However, the tanks can't be placed next to each other.
ただし戦車は　縦　横　隣同士に
並べて配置してはならない」。
（ギャモン）戦車の数字は何だ？
What about the numbers?
That indicates the firing range of each tank.
（スピーカー・デモリションマン）「それは各戦車の
主砲の射程距離である。→
この数字内に　他の戦車を
配置してはならない。→
You may not put a tank in another's range.
You also can't put a tank in a position that would allow it to fire outside the field.
また　射程距離が　フィールド外になる
ような配置をしてもいけない。→
以上　ミッションは全部で３つである」。
That is all. You've got three missions to clear.
So the numbers on the tanks are the hint?
戦車の数字が手がかりってわけか。
フッ！　いい機会だ。
Great!
俺の下がった賞金　目いっぱい
上げてやろうじゃねえか！
I'll use this chance to make my slumping bounty skyrocket!
それでは　戦闘開始！
Begin combat!
心の声
（レイツェル）どうなってるの!?
エニグマは　一体…。
What's going on?
What is Enigma thinking?
Is it wrong to pick the university where my crush goes?
好きな人のために大学を
選ぶのって　不真面目かしら…。
あぁ～　私にも　早く
運命の人が現れてほしいです～。
I wish I had someone destined for me like that too.
ん？　あれ
井藤さんじゃ…。
ん？
Look, isn't that Itou?
First, cross out where I can't put the tanks.
心の声
（ギャモン）まずは　戦車を置けない
場所を潰していく。→
That's how to solve this puzzle.
それが　このパズルの正攻法だ。→
But doing it in my head is really difficult.
しかし　頭の中だけで解くとなると
とてつもなくヘビーなパズルだぜ。
Passed point 4. No abnormalities at codes 10 and 604.
第４ポイントを通過。　コード　イチマル
および　ロクマルヨンに異常なし。
どうだね？　我が輩の戦略は。
How do you like my great strategy?
I clear out Daimon Kaito and a bunch of other high-priority targets at once.
（スピーカー・デモリションマン）
「大門カイトをはじめ
重要ターゲットを一堂に集めて→
一挙に　せん滅する。→
しかも　その引き金を引くのは
最弱の　ターゲットＢ」。
All this by using the weakest target, B.
（パイプに　ぶつかる音）
（ギャモン）あっ　ものすげえ痛ぇ！
That hurt a lot!
Your bounty is a measly $640k. I get a huge return for the lowest possible risk.
（デモリションマン）
貴様の賞金額は　所詮６４万ドル。→
最小のリスクで
最大の成果を引き出す。→
これぞ　我が輩の天才的戦略。
I'm such a genius to come up with this strategy!
（モニター・ギャモン）
「ザケんじゃねえ！」。
ん？
Eat crap!
後悔させてやるぜ！→
I'll make you regret it!
Choosing me was the biggest mistake of your life!
俺を選んだのは
最大の戦略ミスだったってな！
よっしゃ～！
Got that!
Pick up Kaito and the others?
（アイリ）カイト先輩たちを迎えに？
エレナさんに誘われたんだけど
カイトたち　道に迷ってるらしくて→
Elena's invited us, but Kaito and the others got lost, so I arrived first.
私だけ
先に着いちゃったもんだから。
水着は？
あ…。
Where's your swimsuit?
He's having a tough time.
（キュービック）苦戦してるね…。
Yeah.
ああ。　ミスなしで解くのは
至難の業だぜ。
Solving it without any mistakes isn't easy.
ガリレオ…。
Galileo...
（スピーカー・デモリションマン）「さっきまでの
威勢は　どこに行った？→
Where did your enthusiasm from earlier go?
You can't even solve puzzles alone now, Target B?
１人では　まともに
パズルも解けないか？　ターゲットＢ」。
You really are just Daimon Kaito's lackey.
（デモリションマン）さすがは
大門カイトの腰巾着だな。
（モニター）
「誰が　カイトの腰巾着だ！→
Who'd you call a lackey?
Who can't solve puzzles alone here?
誰が　１人じゃ
パズルも解けねえだ！」。
（ギャモン）しゃらくせえ事
言ってんじゃねえ！
Stop spouting nonsense, fatty!
Hell yeah!
っしゃ～！　次が　ラスト…。
（画面の切り替わる音）
The next one is the last!
…って　なにぃ!?→
Wait what?!
マスが増えてマス!?
There are more spaces now?
フフフフフ！　誰も　フィールドの大きさが
一定とは言ってない。
No one said the field size wouldn't change.
（スピーカー・デモリションマン）
「さあ　どうする？　ターゲットＢ！→
What now, Target B?
僅かな残り時間で　これまで以上に
難解なパズルが解けるのかな？」。
Can you solve such a difficult puzzle in such a short time?
もう　間に合わない…。
We're done for.
まあ　黙って見てろよ。
Just watch.
俺は知ってる。　あいつは
どんだけ　たたきのめされようが→
I know him.
You can beat him all you want, but he's still gonna hang on, never giving up.
しぶとく　どこまでも
食らいついてきやがる。
He's a real pain in the ass!
そんな
めんどくせえ野郎だってな。
アーッハッハッハッハッハ！
My strategy was successful! You're dead, Target B!
我が輩の戦略の勝利である！
これで　おしまいだ　ターゲットＢ！
I'm not Target B.
（モニター・ギャモン）
「ターゲットＢなんかじゃねえ」。
何!?
What?
俺は　カイトの腰巾着でもねえ。
I'm not Kaito's lackey either.
俺は俺だ！　逆之上ギャモンだ！
I am me! The mighty Sakanoue Gammon!
No way!
まさか…。
But you won't make it!
だが　もう間に合わん。
間に合ってたまるか！
I won't let you make it!
間に合わせんだよ！→
I'll make it if it kills me!
俺は　ガリレオの…　逆之上ギャモン様だ！
I'm the great Galileo, Sakanoue Gammon!
よっしゃ！　やっぱり
めんどくせえぜ　お前は！
Hell yeah!
You really are a pain in the ass, man!
心の声
（レイツェル）エニグマ…！
Enigma!
Impossible! My strategy couldn't possibly fail!
そんな！
我が輩の戦略が　敗れただと!?
か…　かくなる上は…→
But now that it's come to this,
撤退～！
（ゴング）
time to retreat!
（デモリションマン）戦略的撤退だ～！
Strategic retreat!
（エレナ）ギャモン！
Gammon!
ったく…　遅いのよ　バカ！
You're late! Dummy!
助かったぜ　ギャモン。
Thanks, Gammon.
別に　てめえのために
やったわけじゃねえ。
うっ…。
It's not like I did it for you.
俺に　ケンカ売ってくるやつは
全力で　ぶっ潰す。
I crush those who come at me with all I've got.
これまでも…　これからもだ！
Just like I've always done. And always will.
あっ　カイト！
（アイリ）皆さ～ん　こっちですよ～！
Kaito!
Hey! This way!
あれっ　レイツェルさんは？
そういえば…。
Where's Raetsel?
Now that you mention it...
Huh? She's gone.
（キュービック）あれっ？　いない。
（ギャモン）どこ行きやがった!?
Where could she have gone?
（ノノハ　タマキ）レイツェルさ～ん。
（アイリ）どこ行ったんでしょうね？
Raetsel!
I wonder where she went.
I'm glad to see you're alive.
（エニグマ）
よかった。　生きていたんだね。
君が無事で
私は　本当に　うれしいよ。
Nothing makes me happier than seeing you alive and well.
Cut it out! You're so shameless!
やめてよ！　しらじらしい。
私　殺されるとこだったのよ!?
I almost died back there!
それでもいいと思っていた。
（レイツェル）えっ？
I thought it was worth the risk.
（エニグマ）そうなっても致し方ないと
思っていたんだ。→
I thought that if you died, that was the way it was meant to be.
だって　君は　ジンの事を
疑い始めていたからね。→
You've started doubting Jin after all.
大門カイトたちに惑わされ→
You almost believed that stupid nonsense about Jin loving puzzles,
「ジンが　パズルを愛していた」
などという　でたらめを→
after being misled by the lies of Daimon Kaito and his friends.
信じかけていた。
うっ…。
いくら　君でも…　それは
あってはならない裏切りだ。→
That is a betrayal not even you can be forgiven for.
だから　僕は　彼に代わって
君を　運命の審判に委ねたんだ。
So I put you to the test of fate in his stead.
ジンを疑った事なんて
一度もないわ。
I've never for a moment doubted Jin.
契約は…　守る。
I'll fulfill my end of the contract.
レイツェル！
あっ。
Raetsel!
それは　よかった…。→
I'm so glad to hear that.
This clears up the misunderstanding.
これで誤解が解けたよ。　君には
ひどい事をしてしまったね。
I did something terrible to you.
どうか　これからも
力を尽くしてくれたまえ。
Please keep working hard
我らの真方ジンのために…。
for the sake of our Makata Jin.
Ah, Raerae!
（エレナ）
どうしたのよ？　昨日は途中…。
（レイツェル）近寄らないで。
What happened? You vanished so suddenly yester—
Stay away from me.
聞いたわ　姫川エレナ。→
I heard that you're one of Daimon Kaito's group too, Himekawa Elena.
あなたも　カイトの仲間だったのね。→
いい？　私は　あなたたちの敵よ。→
Don't you get it?
I'm your enemy.
私は　大門カイトを
全てのパズラーを　せん滅する。
I'll annihilate all puzzlers, including Daimon Kaito.
ジンのため…
どんな手を使ってでも！
For Jin's sake, I won't be picky about my methods anymore.
ありがとう。
昨日は楽しかったわ。
Thanks, by the way.
Yesterday was fun.
匂い…　消えちゃった。
Her scent's gone.
（エニグマ）今回は　期せずして
子猫に　お仕置きができたよ。
This time, some scolding got our kitten back on the right track.
でも　子猫は気まぐれだからねえ。
フフフ…。
Alas, kittens tend to be quite willful.
（メランコリィ）
本当に困った野良猫ですわ。
This one especially. Isn't that right, Mister?
ね…　おじ様。
Preview